Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Falcon !
Here, this’s my daddy’s Falcon.
Thanks, Tsubasa, but will
you be okay if I keep this ?
No, I'm not !
Oh no, the Yamato crew has rebelled…?!
Yeah, and I've been summoned by the security bureau.
Did you know ?
No.
They must've been worried about me,
but I feel like I was left behind.
Only me. Only me…
This is the flagship Andromeda.
Deploy the Aldebaran, Apollo Norm, Achilles, Antares, and the Class-Ds on both wings.
Launch fighters.
All ships, take multi-tier formation.
Each ship, eliminate the target in each
corresponding area within ten seconds.
All ships, begin firing cannons.
Come to think of it, it's unusual for that
many ships to be built in only three years.
Time Fault…? Could it be real ?
I don't think it's a joke.
The Yamato took off even
though it was an act of rebellion.
You're right.
We can't turn back now.
Well then, we'd better get going.
There were deserters from the fleet which
was conducting exercises in Jupiter's orbit.
If we allow one exception,
everything will fall apart.
That's what this is all about.
I’ll secure the Yamato...
...no matter what the outcome will be.
Pursuit team, move out.
Deputy Commander, how many of the former Yamato squadron pilots are participating in this exercise ?
There were eight, all of whom deserted.
However, thirty of their students are
still participating in the exercise.
There's a possibility of rebellion.
Bring all thirty of them to this ship.
Aye, sir.
We've been ordered to hunt for the
big one those rats are heading to.
We’re getting closer to the asteroid belt.
I know this is for camouflage, but it's
dangerous without the wave motion shield.
We have to bear with it until the warp drive is ready.
I’m afraid that it will take another five hours until the wave motion coil is replaced.
We're in the Defense Force's front
yard until we leave the Solar System.
Get yourself ready and focus on surveillance.
Right.
Analyzer.
Yes ?
Can you access Niimi's personal file ?
I can.
Good. Search for the term “Izumo Plan.”
You should go.
You said you saw a vision, Sabu.
If so, you must go.
Makoto…
Why is the Yamato flying again ?
What's with them all of a sudden ?!
Takuma, watch your six and evade.
Roger.
Damn, we're both Earthlings…
I think I know why the Yamato’s flying.
It must be our turn.
For what ?
We were glad when Iscandar offered to help, right ?
We heard the voice of someone asking for help.
This time, it's our turn.
That’s why the Yamato’s flying…
…according to the set order, don’t you think so ?
We did our best during the last war.
Nobody knew what the outcome would be.
It didn’t matter.
Both Sabu and I are living our lives honestly.
That’s all I want to tell Tsubasa.
So, be a cool dad…
…for Tsubasa's sake…
…and for me.
Makoto…
Go to the Yamato.
What the hell was that ?!
A powerful electro-magnetic pulse…
We can’t ID friend or foe. Why…?
You can only use your guns.
Who is this ?
Pilot skills will make the difference.
I see.
If missiles and radar are useless,
I can outdo them with my skills.
Good. You've got it.
Garmillas…
As I told you before, Garmillas owes the Yamato.
The Yamato has left Earth once again on a lonely journey.
This time, it’s our turn.
Ambassador Barrel, Earth has its own way of doing things.
That's why...
...I'm following our principles.
Rebellion, huh ?
Those who've been to Iscandar
seem to be detached from reality.
This ship will commence pursuit by itself.
The target is the insurgent ship Yamato.
We're lucky this section wasn't part of the refit.
Indeed.
But are those remains of the Izumo Plan really useful ?
Spacecraft detected approaching
from the upper starboard side.
Here they come.
Some of them are identified.
It's the space fighter/attacker Cosmo Tiger II.
I forbid opening fire until I give the order.
Don't start the fight from our side.
Fifteen seconds until contact.
Spacecraft code identified.
They're the Yamamoto team
from the Moon Space Corps.
Open the hatch and bring the Cosmo Tiger team in.
Alright.
They came.
Yay  !
Yo.
It’s been a while.
That Garmillas spacecraft that joined us…
Yeah, it’s from the Embassy.
Lieutenant Junior Grade Keyman,
what's the meaning of this ?
As I said, I wish to be on the Yamato as an adviser.
The journey to Telezart is unprecedented, but the knowledge of Garmillas will become useful.
If so, only a route map and…
I insist on remaining aboard.
Why not, Acting Captain ?
We are short-handed.
Hey, Shima.
Ship detected at 12 o’clock.
Rapidly closing in at 32 S-knot.
Range, 0.7 light seconds. 130 until contact.
It's the Andromeda.
Wave motion shield ?!
Replacing the last circuit.
Message from the Andromeda.
On the main panel.
So, the dead souls are leading you to where ?
Acting Captain Kodai, turn around.
There's a chance a serious
crisis is about to break out in space.
What if it can't be stopped by the Yamato alone ?
Calm down.
You have to face reality first.
By a reality that leads to a wrong future ?
I'll say it one last time.
Turn around.
I refuse.
What a shame…
They’re coming !
Class-1 battle stations !
Shima, set course for the asteroid belt and go in.
Go in ?!
But the wave motion shield is still…
Hurry. I have an idea.
Distance to the Andromeda is 0.3 light seconds.
Launch a preemptive strike.
Get the graviton spread ready.
Target the Yamato.
Fire !
The asteroids ahead have vanished !
Calm down. It's out of range.
Side depth-charge launcher, get ready.
Fire !
Emit magnetron wave.
Target acquired.
Fire !
All on target.
What is that ?!
Asteroid ship…
What an antique trick…
Chief Engineer, hold for one minute !
Release camouflage !
Maximize electromagnetic induction.
Rotate rapidly for ship defense.
Start rotating.
Rock volume decreased to 50%.
Please hold on.
Rock volume 30%.
This is Enomoto. Everything's done.
Close the electromagnetic induction.
Concentrate wave motion shield at the bow.
Contact with the Andromeda in ten seconds.
Prepare for impact !
What a stubborn lad your son is, Mr. Okita.
Captain, should we turn and pursue ?
Captain !
Emergency message from HQ.
On screen.
HQ has a directive to all Earth ships in the Solar System.
Terminate pursuit of the Yamato.
The treason charge against the
Yamato crew has been dropped.
I repeat. The treason charge against
the Yamato crew has been dropped.
What is that supposed to mean ?
I did say we were useful.
I appreciate this, Prime Minister.
Are you satisfied ?
The Time Fault will not only change the
future of Earth, but of Garmillas, as well.
If we corner those who've
gained knowledge of it…
Rumor has it that the secret was
leaked by the Garmillas embassy staff.
If that's true, it's a terrible thing.
We'll launch a thorough investigation.
Anyhow, no charges against the Yamato’s rebellion.
HQ retroactively approved the Yamato’s expedition to Telezart as an independent task force.
And you’re fine with that, right ?
Exactly as you planned.
To the Yamato crew, as the Chief,
I issue you new orders.
Get to the bottom of the imminent crisis, and then…
…return home safely.
That'll be all.
I handed it over to them according to your order.
All of them requested transfer to the Yamato.
You anticipated this outcome, Captain ?
I was going to use them as hostages if the
situation called for it, so this just happened.
This is Kato Saburo,
former Yamato squadron commander.
Request permission to come aboard.
Kato !
Kato’s here !
Tsubasa, this is the Yamato. Your dad’s ship.
I wish I could let you see it.
Episode 5
Face off ! Yamato vs Andromeda
Tawamureru yuragu tsuki no kagami
The reflection of the moon is blurry and capricious
Kodai Susumu:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Analyzer:
Kato Saburo:
Kato Makoto:
Kato Tsubasa:
Ono Daisuke
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Cho
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Sato Rina
Takamori Natsumi
Yamamoto Akira:
Shinohara Hiroki:
Saijo Miki:
Enomoto Isami:
Sawamura Sho:
Takuma Takeshi:
Tokishi Ayuto:
Koda Minoru:
Yamanami Osamu:
Todou Heikuro:
Serizawa Kotetsu:
Barrel:
Keyman:
Prime Minister:
Deputy Commander:
Operator:
Tanaka Rie
Hirata Daisuke
Moriya Satomi
Tsuda Kenjiro
Chikaki Yuya
Kijima Ryuichi
Komoto Yusuke
Fujinuma Kento
Ebara Masashi
Kojima Toshihiko
Genda Tessho
Terasoma Masaki
Kamiya Hiroshi
Mikimoto Masayuki
Ichinowatari Hiroaki
Yano Masaaki
Kokoro tokasu yuubina kami no itazura
Graceful God's mischief mesmerizes my heart
Uchi ni himeta awai omoide ni
There's a faint memory hidden within
Iki wo fukikomu no michite yukumade
Breathe life into it until it's full
Hibiku anata no mune no kodou wo
I hear a heartbeat echoing through
Watashi hitori janai
I am not alone
Saewataru sora ni inori
I pray to the wide open sky
Atarashii ichinichi no maku ga aketeyuku
The curtain opens on a brand new day
Preview
The size of the enemy is too large
for the Yamato to handle by itself.
I find it contradictory that we'd abandon
drowning people right before our eyes.
That’s too risky.
The Yamato currently has a serious weakness.
You should know what it is.
Commence the 11th planet rescue operation.
Episode 06
Deadly Battle on the 11th Planet